This is crazy. This is stupid. This is love.
Crazy, Stupid, Love. is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Glenn Ficarra.
Cal Weaver is living the American dream.
He has a good job, a beautiful house, great children
and a beautiful wife, named Emily.
Cal's seemingly perfect life unravels, however, when he learns
that Emily has been unfaithful and wants a divorce.
Over 40 and suddenly single, Cal is adrift in the fickle world of dating.
Enter, Jacob Palmer, a self-styled player who takes Cal under his
wing and teaches him how to be a hit with the ladies.
Cal, played by Steve Carell.
Jacob, played by Ryan Gosling.
Emily, played by Julianne Moore.
Hannah, played by Emma Stone.
Jessica, played by Lio Tipton.
Robbie, played by Jonah Bobo.
Crazy, Stupid, Love.
is a 2011 American romantic comedy film directed by Glenn
Ficarra and John Requa and written by Dan Fogelman.
It stars Steve Carell, Ryan Gosling, Julianne Moore, Emma Stone,
John Carroll Lynch, Marisa Tomei, and Kevin Bacon.
It follows a series of interconnected love stories centered on a recently separated man,
played by Carrell, who learns how to be more romantic and charm women.
The film was theatrically released in the United
States on July 29, 2011, by Warner Bros.
It received positive reviews from critics and was a box office success,
grossing over $145 million worldwide against a $50 million budget.
It was nominated for Best Comedy at the 17th Critics' Choice Awards, while Gosling was nominated for
Best Actor in a Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy at the 69th Golden Globe Awards.
The film explores themes of friendship, soulmates,
marriage crisis, midlife crisis, babysitter.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.